Guide to the Ved Mehta Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ved Mehta papers
1924-2011
GEN MSS 744
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
116.04
(212 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
The papers document the life and work of Ved Mehta and include writings, correspondence, family archival material, personal papers, academic records, financial records, research and subject files, printed material, photographs, and electronic files. Writings includes drafts of (and for some, extensive research files for) all of Mehta's major works from 1957 to 2004. Drafts of writings and Mehta's outgoing correspondence are typewritten. Subject files and correspondence relate not only to Mehta's life and work, but also to his family, to acquaintances such as Ethel Clyde, and to organizations such as the Arkansas School for the Blind, Pomona College, and Oxford University.
Mehta, Ved, 1934-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ved Mehta on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1996-2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 91-92 and 199 (Engagement diaries): Restricted until 2031.
Boxes 100-114 and 169-183 (Financial records): Restricted until 2031.
Box 200 (Restricted papers): Restricted until 2031.
Computer disks in boxes 122: Restricted fragile material. Use reference copy.
Audio tapes in boxes 122: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 17-18 (New Yorker book files): Open for research. Restriction expired in 2011. Box 197 and 198: Open for research. Restriction expired in 2011.
Arrangement
Organized into five groupings: July 1996 Acquisition, July 1999 Acquisition, February 2000 Acquisition, March 2005 Acquisition, and April 2011 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence can be found in each of the four groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Ved Mehta, 1934-
Ved Mehta, Indian-American author of novels, family biographies, and essays, was born in 1934 in Lahore (then an Indian city, now part of Pakistan). Blind since childhood, he attended boarding schools in India and in the United States. He continued his education at Pomona College and Harvard University, eventually becoming an American citizen. Among his many writings are A Portrait of India (1970), the series of family biographies Continents of Exile (1972-1993), and the collected essays Fly and the Fly-Bottle (1966) and A Ved Mehta Reader: The Craft of the Essay (1998). He was a staff writer at The New Yorker from 1961 to 1994.
Scope and Contents
The papers document the life and work of Ved Mehta and include writings, correspondence, family archival material, personal papers, academic records, financial records, research and subject files, printed material, photographs, and electronic files. Writings includes drafts of (and for some, extensive research files for) all of Mehta's major works from 1957 to 2004. Drafts of writings and Mehta's outgoing correspondence are typewritten. Subject files and correspondence relate not only to Mehta's life and work, but also to his family, to acquaintances such as Ethel Clyde, and to organizations such as the Arkansas School for the Blind, Pomona College, and Oxford University.
Language(s)
Materials chiefly in English.
American literature; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Biography; Blind -- United States -- Biography; East Indian Americans; India -- Social life and customs; Photographs; Born digital; Electronic documents; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Mehta, Ved, 1934-; Clyde, Ethel, 1879-; Arkansas School for the Blind; Pomona College (Claremont, Calif.); University of Oxford
- July 1996 Acquisition, circa 1924-1995; 68.25; (122 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Ved Mehta on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1996.
  General note
  Formerly classed as Uncat MS Vault 768.
  - Correspondence
    - Personal
      - Personal U.S.A., 1958-1960 (Box 1)
      - Personal England, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
      - Personal Family, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
      - Personal India, 1958-1966; 2 (Box 1)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1958-1966 (Box 1)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1961-1962; 2 (Box 1)
      - Personal England, 1962-1963; 2 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1963-1964; 2 (Box 1)
      - Personal England, 1964 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
      - Personal Family, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1965 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Active U.S.A., 1966 (Box 2)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1967 (Box 2)
      - Personal England, 1967 (Box 2)
      - Personal Family, 1967 (Box 2)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1967 (Box 2)
      - Personal Correspondence, Elsewhere, Active, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Personal Family, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1968 (Box 2)
      - Personal England Active, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Personal U.S.A. Active, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Personal India, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Personal Family, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Personal England, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Personal India Active (Box 2)
      - Personal Active U.S.A., 1970 (Box 2)
      - Personal Family Active, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Personal Elsewhere Active, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Personal England, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Personal (various), 1971; 5 (Box 2)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1972 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1973 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1973 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1974 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1975 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1975 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1975 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1975 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1975 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1976 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1976 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1976 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1976 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1976 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1977; 2 (Box 3)
      - Personal England, 1977 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1977 (Box 3)
      - Personal Family, 1977 (Box 3)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1977 (Box 3)
      - Personal India, 1978 (Box 3)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1978 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1978 (Box 4)
      - Personal Family, 1978 (Box 4)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1978 (Box 4)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1979 (Box 4)
      - Personal India, 1979 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1979 (Box 4)
      - Personal Family, 1979 (Box 4)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1979 (Box 4)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1980 (Box 4)
      - Personal India, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Personal Family, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1981; 2 (Box 4)
      - Personal India, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Personal Family, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1982; 2 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Personal India, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Personal Family, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1983; 2 (Box 4)
      - Personal India, 1983 (Box 4)
      - Personal England, 1983 (Box 5)
      - Personal Family, 1983; 2 (Box 5)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1983 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1984 (Box 5)
      - Personal England, 1984 (Box 5)
      - Personal India, 1984 (Box 5)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1984 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1985 (Box 5)
      - Personal India, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Personal England, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Personal Family Active, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Personal Elsewhere, 1985-87 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1986 (Box 5)
      - Personal England, 1986-87 (Box 5)
      - Personal India, 1986-87 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1987 (Box 5)
      - Personal England, 1988-89 (Box 5)
      - Personal India, 1988-91 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1988-89 (Box 5)
      - From Friends on Father's Death, 1986 (Box 5)
      - Condolences on Father's Death from fans, 1986 (Box 5)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1990-1994; 5 (Box 5)
      - Personal India, 1994 (Box 5)
      - Personal England, 1990-1994; 4 (Box 6)
      - Special Correspondence, 1960-1992 (Box 6)
      - Family Archives, 1970 (Box 6)
      - Archives England, 1970 (Box 6)
      - Archives U.S.A., 1970 (Box 6)
      - Personal India Dead, 1969 (Box 6)
      - Elsewhere Dead, 1969 (Box 6)
      - Family Archives, 1967 (Box 6)
      - England Archives, 1968 (Box 6)
      - Elsewhere Archives, 1968 (Box 6)
      - Archives Family, 1968 (Box 7)
      - U.S.A. Dead, 1969 (Box 7)
      - Personal U.S.A. Archives, 1968 (Box 7)
      - Family Dead, 1969; 2 (Box 7)
      - England Dead, 1969 (Box 7)
      - England archives, 1967 (Box 7)
      - Archives, 1968 (Box 7)
      - Archives misc, 1965-1966; 2 (Box 7)
      - Archives: Personal U.S. correspondence Jan-Aug, 1962; 2 (Box 8)
      - Archives: U.S.A., 1967 (Box 8)
      - Archives: Personal Correspondence Elsewhere, 1959-1966; 2 (Box 8)
      - Archives: Personal U.S. correspondence, Sept-Dec, 1962 (Box 8)
      - Personal Family, 1965-1966; 2 (Box 8)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1963 (Box 9)
      - Personal U.S.A., 1962 (Box 9)
      - Miscellanesous archives, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
      - Archives U.S., 1964; 2 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence archives, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
      - Archives Personal U.S., 1961; 2 (Box 9)
      - Archives: Indian correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 10)
      - American archives, 1958-1960 (Box 10)
      - England Archives, 1964-1966; 2 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence: Indian Journals, 1959-1965 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence: English archives, 1962; 2 (Box 10)
      - Oxford archives (personal correspondence England), 1958-1961 (Box 11)
      - Archives: Family correspondence (India), 1956-1964 (Box 11)
      - Family correspondence in India, 1956-1964 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence England archives, 1963 (Box 11)
      - Personal U.S.A. Archives, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Fan Mail
      - Fan letters, 1960-1986; 19 (Box 12)
      - Fan letters, 1988-1995; 5 (Box 13)
      - Fan letters, 1984-1987; 4 (Box 14)
    - Ved Mehta's Publishers & Agents
      - Publishers, 1983-1986; 4 (Box 14)
      - Publishers, 1964-1996; 11 (Box 15)
      - McIntosh & Otis, 1957-1965 (Box 16)
      - Laurence Pollinger, 1958-1967 (Box 16)
      - Atlantic Monthly, 1955-1966; 2 (Box 16)
      - Collins, 1957 (Box 16)
      - Harper & Row, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
    - Periodicals (soliciting work from Ved Mehta)
      - American Periodicals Active, 1968 (Box 16)
      - American Periodicals, 1958-1965 (Box 16)
  - Writings and Research Files
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker
      - Chapter IX: On the Move (Box 17)
      - Manuscript Chapters VI-VII (Box 17)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes 1 computer disk (stored in: Box 122)
        Existence and Location of Copies
        Electronic files are available through Access Services (Disk #4).
      - Untitled, page 1-13 (Box 17)
      - Untitled manuscript, no page numbers (Box 17)
      - Chapter VI: Embarking on a Dangerous Profession (Box 17)
      - Chapter V: Scholar Manque (Box 17)
      - Chapter V: Scholar Manque (Box 17)
      - Chapter IV: The Sighted Book (Box 17)
      - Chapter III: Ver-ri-tas (Box 17)
      - Chapter III: Ver-ri-tas, Aug 23, 1995 (Box 17)
      - Chapter II: The Two Circles (Box 17)
      - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker Chapter I: A Story in the New Yorker. Revised June, July, 1995 (Box 17)
      - Ms. Gould's Second Reading, Feb: Chapters 7 and 8, 1996 (Box 17)
      - New Yorker Manuscript. March 1. Ch. 1-7 (partial), Incomplete but final version, 1996 (Box 17)
      - Chapter IX: In and Out of the Dakota (Box 17)
      - New Yorker book: Chapter 1, March 13, 1995 (Box 18)
      - New Yorker book, Ch. 1, draft sent to Ms. Gould, March, 1995 (Box 18)
      - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker Ms. Gould changes January, 1995 (Box 18)
      - "The Two Circles" Ms. Gould's Copy (Box 18)
      - Chapter IX: On the Move (Box 18)
      - New Yorker copies of Personal History Chapters 1-3 (Box 18)
    - "Articles and Stories"
      Clippings and photocopies of articles and stories by Ved Mehta.
      - Articles and stories, 1952-1968; 14 (Box 19)
      - Articles and stories, 1969-1980; 12 (Box 20)
      - Articles and stories, 1981-1994; 11 (Box 21)
    - Ideas for New Yorker Articles
      - Annals of Crime (Box 22)
      - Bob Burchfield (Box 22)
      - Chess (Box 22)
      - Classics correspondence (Box 22)
      - Coolidge (Box 22)
      - Pathfinders (Box 22)
      - Cows (Box 22)
      - India: Holy Relic (Box 22)
      - India: Jews (Box 22)
      - India: Popcorn King (Box 22)
      - India: Nuclear (Box 22)
      - Economics: Samuelson (Box 22)
      - Sir Hugh Foot (Box 22)
      - General (Box 22)
      - Robert Graves (Box 22)
      - Grosvenor House (Box 22)
      - Hi Fi (Box 22)
      - Indrani (Box 22)
      - Prof. Khorana (Box 22)
      - Linear A & B (Box 22)
      - Linguistics (Box 22)
      - Mass Education (Box 22)
      - Z. Moyeddin (Box 22)
      - Shakespeare reading (Box 22)
      - Talk ideas (Box 22)
      - Tata (Box 22)
      - Theatre Arts (Box 22)
      - Television Professor (Box 22)
      - U. Thant (Box 22)
      - Arthur Waley (Box 22)
    - Indian Journal
      - Galley proofs, parts I-IV, 1967; 6 (Box 23)
      - New Yorker Proofs of Indian Journal, 1960s; 2 (Box 23)
      - New Yorker Proofs of Indian Journal (continued), 1960s (Box 24)
      - Technical Assistance
        (also titled "A phonograph, A Radio, A Car and A Refrigerator")
        - Notes, 1961, undated; 2 (Box 24)
        - Manuscript, 1962? (Box 24)
        - MS - Double spaced, original copy, undated (Box 24)
    - A Family Affair
      - Final copy (Box 24)
      - 2nd to final copy (titled "A New India?") (Box 25)
    - Articles and stories
      - Vedi: Daddyji's corrections (Box 25)
      - Refugees, etc. (Box 25)
      - Refugees, etc.: Daddyji's Corrections (Box 25)
      - Daddyji material: Father's Memoir (Box 26)
      - Manuscript changes/Book: Daddyji, 3 (Box 26)
      - Daddyji manuscript (setting copy) (Box 26)
      - Sunset manuscript (Box 27)
      - Delinquent Chacha, Esq. MS and notes (Box 27)
      - Correspondence, general reaction (Box 27)
      - The Music Master
        - The Music Master (Box 27)
        - Talk Stories (Box 27)
      - Call Girl
        - Call Girl, letters (Box 27)
        - Letter from Delhi, 1977 (Box 27)
        - Letter from New Delhi, The New India (Penguin Books) (Box 27)
      - Linguistics
        - Correspondence (Box 27)
      - Indian Journal
        - Manuscript, inserts (Box 27)
        - Manuscript, Kushwant Singh (Box 27)
        - Forward Areas (Box 27)
        - Conclusion (Box 27)
        - Material for revisions already made (Box 27)
    - Mamaji Manuscript and Proofs
      - Mamaji - Father's Proofs, 2 (Box 28)
      - Mamaji: Finished Copy (Later Pages) Corrected by Daddyji (Box 28)
    - Chachaji Manuscript
      - Manuscript: Chachaji, 3 (Box 28)
      - English replies, London summer, 1972 (Box 28)
      - London Winter, 1972-73 (Box 28)
    - Gandhi Material
      - Gandhi book: correspondence with sources, 2 (Box 29)
      - Proofs for reviewers, 3 (Box 29)
      - Final Manuscript I (Box 30)
      - Final Manuscript II (Box 30)
      - Final Manuscript III (Box 30)
    - Up At Oxford material / Various Oxford
      - Ms. Gould 2nd Go-Round. Part I, 2 (Box 30)
      - Ms. Gould 2nd go-round. Part Two, 2 (Box 30)
      - Ms. Gould 2nd go-round. Part Two (continued) (Box 31)
      - Ms. Gould - First Go-Round, 3 (Box 31)
      - A version of ending (Box 31)
      - Manuscript of chapters VI and IV, plus excerpts (Box 31)
      - Manuscript of chapter X (Box 31)
      - Final rough MS April, MS. Gould's corrected copy, I, 1991 (Box 32)
      - Final rough MS April, Ms. Gould's corrected copy, II, 1991 (Box 32)
      - Up at Oxford, full manuscript, 3 (Box 33)
      - Notes for the Oxford book, 5 (Box 33)
      - Notes for the Oxford book (continued), 2 (Box 34)
      - Jasper Section (Ireland, Christies hospital, 11-plus sample) (Box 34)
      - Jasper Section Exam papers, 1957-58; 2 (Box 34)
      - History of Arkansas School for the Blind for Jasper Chapter (Oxford Book) (Box 34)
      - Fraenkel (Jasper chapter), 1972 (Box 34)
      - Third Year/Schools/Wilson Southam, 1974 (Box 34)
      - Key to files on computer (Box 34)
      - John Prest (2nd year) (Box 34)
      - 2nd year Card School (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous Oxford book data, 7 (Box 34)
      - Career 1959: Letter to Sir Raghaven, July 30, 1958 (Box 35)
      - Coolidge
        - Ockenden HF (Box 35)
        - Barron HF (Box 35)
        - Tomkys HF (Box 35)
        - Oakeshott HF (Box 35)
        - Bingham HF (Box 35)
        - Gregson HF (Box 35)
        - Keen HF (Box 35)
      - Alistair McKann: Oxford Volume (Box 35)
      - Beethoven (King Oxford?) (Box 35)
      - Alasdair Clayre - sent MS (Box 35)
      - Oxford - The Dreaming Spires I (Box 35)
      - First Year/Hilary term/Hill, 1957 (Box 35)
      - Michaelmas - Kozol, 1958 (Box 35)
      - Dr. Ata - Hungary (Box 35)
      - Dom and his group - MS (Box 35)
      - Manuscript: Dom (Box 35)
      - Dom and Group, One Version - Weeks Book Project (Box 35)
      - Father. Mrs Clyde: Current Manuscript (Box 35)
      - Third year/Oxmantown group (Box 35)
      - Oxmantown MS (Box 35)
      - In the Force & Rd. of Casualty VIII (Box 35)
      - Friends Apart X (Box 35)
      - The Tolling of Great Tom XI (Box 35)
      - Thelma Daphne Smith Schools (Box 35)
      - Afterword? Misc (Box 35)
      - Extra PP. back from Shawn (Box 36)
      - The Tolling of Great Tom: June 22, Personal History, 1992 (Box 36)
      - Heterosexual legislation checking (Box 36)
      - Oxford - Sullivan, Snedden (Box 36)
      - Winchester scholars third year (Box 36)
      - Some of Mamaji or Daddyji? (Box 36)
      - First days: Galbraith (Box 36)
      - First year: political issues, 1956 (Box 36)
      - First Year: school hierarchy, 1956 (Box 36)
      - First Year: Gang, chaps, 2nd Hall and public school (Box 36)
      - President's book and Mr. Food's book, 1957-58 (Box 36)
      - Tutorial system (Box 36)
      - First year: tutorial system and bad teaching (Box 36)
      - Aga Khan Gambling, miscellaneous notes and corrections by father (Box 36)
      - Galbraith: questionable use, 1956 (Box 36)
      - Oxford volume material: questionable use (Box 36)
      - Article on Russel Meiggs, questionable use (Box 36)
      - Bank statements, questionable use, 1956-58 (Box 36)
      - College history, questionable use, probably dead (Box 36)
      - Young Men's Dreams, 1958 (Box 36)
      - Oxford: questionable use, 1956-59 (Box 36)
      - History schools cards: questionable use, 2 (Box 37)
      - Robert Oakshott, First year political issues, Dead, 1956-1957 (Box 37)
      - Daddyji: West Germany dentist story miscellaneous corrections and notes from father, dead (Box 37)
      - Tutorials: English history, 600-1215, Volume II (Box 37)
      - Tutorials: English History 1215-1485, Volume II (Box 37)
      - Christ Church Meadow Road, Dead (Box 37)
      - Afterlife (Box 37)
      - Om's college story, undated; 1; 00:37:07; The program begins and ends abruptly. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 122, Item barcode 39002099360910)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access services for further information.
      - Oxford: Computer Disks
        3 computer disks
        Available through Access Services (Disks #5, #6, #7).
      - Correspondence Rhodes Dead, 1955-56 (Box 37)
      - Oxford dead: Jasper school contemporaries (Box 37)
      - Fraenkel, 1957-58 (Box 37)
      - Diana Brook, 1957-58 (Box 37)
      - Discard (Box 37)
      - Book, 1957 (Box 37)
      - Post Oxford (scraps), undated (Box 37)
      - David Cecil quote about exams, 1986 (Box 37)
      - Afterword, undated (Box 37)
      - Alastair McCann, undated (Box 37)
      - Career 1959, undated (Box 37)
      - DOM-Post Oxford (Box 37)
      - Jasper's Manuscript changes (Box 38)
      - Oxford book revisions (Box 38)
      - Jasper chapter: Gould and father's revisions (Box 38)
      - Ms. Gould's changes chap. IV (Box 38)
      - Ms. Gould's revisions, chap. I-III (Box 38)
      - Oxford Book: Ms Gould's last changes, 2 (Box 38)
      - Oxford: ch. I-III minor revisions, subsequent to Ms. Gould's proofs (Box 39)
      - Early Norton jacket material, Oxford (Box 39)
      - BK Revisions, Oxford (Box 39)
      - Sheltering the World within the World: Overflow (Box 39)
      - For checking: Oxford (Box 39)
      - Mamaji's first visit abroad, 1956 (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 39)
      - Third Year: Roger Scott (Box 39)
      - Trinity Song Checking, 1957 (Box 39)
      - Jasper's Exams, Biography of Ireland Checking, 1957-58 (Box 39)
      - Balliol Clubs Checking, 1957-58 (Box 39)
      - Staircase 10 Rms. Checking, 1957 (Box 39)
      - Christopher Hill Checking, 1957 (Box 39)
      - Jasper's room: staircase 16, checking, 1956 (Box 39)
      - Scout Checking, 1956 (Box 39)
      - Father's lectures checking, 1956 (Box 39)
      - Young Man's Dream: correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 39)
      - History Exams checking, 1959 (Box 40)
      - History schools checking, 1959 (Box 40)
      - Harold MacMillan checking (Box 40)
      - The Beat Hotel: Book of photos (Box 40)
      - Lord Oxmantown checking, 1958-59 (Box 40)
      - John Masefield checking Spring, 1958 (Box 40)
      - Program for the Glyndebourne Festival Opera (Box 40)
      - Balliol history checking (Box 40)
      - Father's proverbs (Box 40)
      - Correspondence checking, 1959 (Box 40)
      - Correspondence checking, 1958 (Box 40)
      - Christ Church Meadow checking (Box 40)
      - Checking: Oxmantown Chapter X (Box 40)
      - Checking: Oxford 1958-59
        - Checking: Father in Oxford (Box 40)
        - Checking: various reviews, Dom (Box 40)
      - Young Man's Dream Manuscript (unpublished) (Box 40)
      - Peter Levi story, checking (Box 40)
      - Thistle Soc., 1957-58 (Box 40)
      - JCR Teas checking, 1956 (Box 40)
      - Checking: Jasper's review of Face to Face (Box 40)
      - Checking: Dean's section: Balliol College Annual Record, 1980 (Box 41)
      - Checking: Journal entries (Box 41)
      - Checking: Oxford 1957-58
        - Checking: Alfred Deller Tavern songs (Oxford manuscript) (Box 41)
        - Checking: Oxford book, 1950s political issues and Robert Oakeshott (Box 41)
        - "U and Non-U" Nancy Mitford's "Noblesse Oblige" (Box 41)
        - Checking: Oxford book, Balogh and Streeten, Balliol Records (Box 41)
        - Checking: correspondence, 1957 (Box 41)
        - Princess Margaret and Townsend (Box 41)
        - Buttery, Frank; W.J. Smith dead, 1956 (Box 41)